sup y'all we just finished recording
this AI episode and my mind is still
buzzing so I won't keep you here in the
introduction for too long but I did want
to give a couple shout outs
um one first head over to ctbb.show and
drop your email in there uh we've got
Jesse Rivera writing some awesome
text-based content that is uh sort of
runs alongside the Pod a Blog cast if
you will
um so definitely check that out also we
have two guests on the Pod today we've
got Daniel measler and uh rezzo or
Joseph Thacker definitely go and give
them a follow on Twitter and definitely
don't forget to check out Daniel
musler's podcast unsupervised learning
some awesome security and AI content
over there alright enjoy the episode
that's right that's right
imagine someone gets access to that
interface right I mean they're just
gonna be like write the extortion email
for me write the ransomware like
and here's who to Target and here's the
actual text that will most likely take
the emails of the person you know that I
that I'm emailing this to analyze it for
the best way to like you know interact
with them and then write their answer
[Music]
anything
all right we're rolling stuff guys
welcome to the pod
dude I'm super excited for this episode
because AI is such a Hot Topic right now
and I just think there's a lot of stuff
to uncover in this area so really
pleased to have rezzo uh and Daniel
musler on for those of you that don't
know these guys you're missing us out
big time if you're not following them on
Twitter both very active both very high
quality content
um I'll go ahead and I'll let you guys
do your own intros but also I wanna I
wanna just say beforehand like
Daniel like
you're the closest thing that I know to
a tech and security philosopher and I
just love that like like at all the
times you put out those essays and stuff
like that they talk about like high
level clock Concepts like backing up
yourself into an llm or like you know
predictions on the future of of it
architecture I love that [__] so that's
that's my little my little tidbit and
Daniel I'll let you introduce yourself
yeah no I appreciate you saying that um
uh so I've been in security for uh I I
think going on like uh 24 years now so
it's been quite a while
uh yeah my my background is in um as you
might expect is um in attacking yeah
assessments
um pen testing mostly on the um absent
side and um and as of like November I've
been totally bitten by this AI thing I
actually joined an AI team um at Apple
and worked there for a number of years
um I wasn't really doing yeah I was I
wasn't really doing AI stuff there it
was just kind of helping them out with
the AI stuff and I was doing some other
security stuff but that's where um I got
my uh intro to it and I did uh Andrew
Eng's full course oh nice of videos yeah
it was crazy uh when was this when was
this happening
This was um I want to say 2017. wow so
you were a real early player in the
space then yeah yeah I've been I've been
following it for quite some time
um but yeah that's what I'm doing now is
like merging the two of uh AI yeah I
love that intro to the podcast as well
you know you talk about how Ai and
security mix together and and how to
create you know that combination it's
really really good content
um rezo what about you man
yeah well I did want to say two quick
things one Daniel is way ahead of that I
mean just look at the name of his
website and uh podcast right yeah and
supervised learning he's already been in
the AI space way ahead of time uh but
then yeah and then also I did want to
say before I intro myself that it's an
absolute honor and pleasure to be
hanging out with you guys today you know
both of you all the people that I
admired and looked up to for years and
then have become friends with um over
the last you know year or two so that's
really exciting yeah I know I um I've
been in security I guess five or six
years now Daniel may have more
experience than me and you I know right
seriously yeah
yeah so I started um with a software
engineering kind of background
um and then moved and transition into
security and kind of did the defensive
stock analyst engineering work while I
was developing the appsec bug Bounty
hacking on the side for a couple years
and then made the switch so now I do SAS
security like hacking SAS apps for app
Omni and then you know bug Bounty and a
lot of bug Bounty Daniel mentioned
yeah yeah exactly and then uh Daniel uh
similar to him and similar to you
honestly Justin have been kind of bit by
the the AI bug lately and so going down
those rabbit holes because we need
people who are willing to Pioneer and
figure it out so we can help keep it
secure and then also find the things
that other people yeah for sure it's
it's a really exciting space and I think
I think um I've got two main directions
that I want to go today with the Pod and
um both of you are sort of fit to one of
them that doesn't mean that the other
one can't jump in on on the other topic
you know please jump in as as you see
fit but the two things that I kind of
want to talk about are how to hack with
AI so using AI to develop hacking tools
and to help our hacking workflow and
then also how to hack AI right how to
take advantage of these newer
Technologies and misconfigurations in
these and uh and find you know
vulnerabilities that we can report so I
figured we'd start out with like how to
use AI for hacking and I was gonna I was
gonna do this a little bit later on in
the flow um Daniel but uh I think I'm
just gonna jump right to it because I'm
really excited to hear about it you got
to tell me about your your personal
setup for uh you know AI sort of
shortcuts and command line tools that
you've been building out because you've
hinted at that to me before and I was
like all right let's discuss it on the
Pod let's discuss on the Pod so now's my
moment yeah yeah absolutely so like I
don't remember when this was it must
have been like 2015 or 2016.
um I announced like this company called
Helios
um and everyone was like congrats you're
going full time but I wasn't going
full-time like um I'm still doing my
main gig I just announced like the
platform
um but basically all it is and I did a
talk about this at Defcon one year
um uh called mechanizing the methodology
and I think like almost everyone and I'm
sure you two as well are using this now
and maybe even were using it before it's
basically I have one mini command for
each thing I want to do
um so I have one called get tlds
the input is any existing domain and I
get all the tlps well I can then pipe
that in to another command which either
takes input from um as a parameter or it
takes it in from SPN
uh which is get sub domains so now I'm
piping from tlds into subdomains and now
I can pipe into find open ports okay and
and what's cool about it is that's
abstracted because I could use Naboo I
could use uh nmap mask scan or whatever
to do that and then so what I have is I
have currently around 39 of these and
then basically forming those into
sentences is what ends up being my Recon
stock and my test oh wow that's cool so
you're kind of building out like a flow
specifically and it's very Linux style
right it's piping directly from one
right into the other and you're
abstracting away all the different tools
you're using this is a really great idea
and a great takeaway for anyone who's
looking to build Recon stuff like even
if it's just creating your own wrapper
just around the tool that's okay you
know like but as long as you're
abstracting it out it becomes your your
flow will be consistent across you know
the the commands that you'll run as as
your your
um your workflow evolves as you change
from you know Naboo to mass scan or
whatever you're jumping around for you
know you'll still be typing the same
commands that muscle memory will still
be the same and you can just interchange
out the back end that's that's really
solid
um you know what what kind of ways do
you see AI coming into this into this uh
flow and evolving your current setup
that you've got there
did we lose them
we might have one thing one thing I know
that he shared with me while he's trying
to connect in there I've seen a little
bit yeah this tooling and one huge thing
with using llms is that you have to be
able to get clean data and and you want
to remove into fluff and so that's one
thing I know some of those cool tools do
is they pull content from web pages and
it just strips out all of the extra tags
it trips out all the extra fluff
um and actually Simon Willison he writes
a lot about Ai and security and just AI
in general he just released a tool
recently that will do the same thing for
python functions so it's a command line
tool that will do like a WebEx search on
on a python code base and then it only
Returns the code for the function that
you search for so you could imagine it
being pipeable where you're saying like
you've got some tool and what it does is
it looks over the code base or whatever
and it tries to help you or improve
certain functions and how does it know
to do that well it needs to have just
the function be returned because you
know it can't ingest the whole the whole
uh yeah project and so that's exactly
what it does it does a loose search and
just Returns the code that's that's
pretty rad and that's something that I
kind of wanted to talk a little bit
about a little bit later with embeddings
is like you know especially when we're
we're building tooling surrounding
um you know it could be Javascript file
analysis it could be
um you know it could be running code and
analyzing open source code or whatever
is you know sure one of the things that
I that's most difficult for me is like
okay now I've got to go find this
function and then there's like six
functions that match this you know
signature for this specific call and
like how do I know which one goes where
and if we had an llm that really
understood like you know the mappings
and and could map out these sort of
Paths of of code that I think that would
be really helpful but um it's hard to
keep all that that's actually
interesting you know because there's
only a certain amount of context window
you've got
yeah that's actually really interesting
though I wonder if it could do it bit by
bit and like slowly draw those
connections that'd be a really neat um
product because I think it would allow
um like if you could pre-run it on a
cloud base and it created those flows
then it would allow the function call
and let's assume it could like compress
it or like that that flow chart would be
a good way for the it would fit into
context it'd be a good way for the llm
to be able to understand what that was
doing and then maybe maybe be able to
you know return better or more coherent
yeah so I mean Code Pilot or um copilot
is is absolutely you know
revolutionizing the development world
right and I just I'm really interested
to see what's going to happen as we try
to apply something like this to the
security realm as well and and see if we
can map out all these various pathways
through the code and and find
vulnerabilities so that's that's
something that that I'm definitely
looking forward to checking out
yeah yeah absolutely and I think it's
going to be the same it's going to it's
the same challenges that they're
overcoming to have to have tools that
are going to help developers write
features in the context of the full app
I think they're going to run through all
of those hurdles and challenges that we
need them to run through right like how
do I ingest and understand this whole
code base right because that's the only
way you're going to be able to implement
a feature at scale similarly when they
run through those same hurdles we're
going to be able to apply it to security
right like find security vulnerabilities
now with the context and the awareness
of the full project yeah for sure and I
know I know I don't well I'm not sure if
it was you or Daniel that dropped into
the into the dock but this GPT engineer
thing did you see that
yeah I put it in there I initially had a
mass section but then I saw that his
section was called how to use AI for
hacking so I dragged it up to his I
wanted to talk yeah man hopefully
hopefully Daniel can reconnect here in a
second but I thought that that was
really cool for like such a cool concept
and something that I hadn't really seen
so let me why don't you talk about that
for just a second I'm gonna go answer a
DM from Daniel see if we can get it back
on
sure perfect yeah I'll explain it to the
audience so uh GPT engineer went from
zero to like 14 000 stars in the in the
past like week uh it's kind of like
another project called small developer
and uh okay that's the one idea is that
yeah I was like I wasn't it sounded
familiar but I thought it had a
different name small developer is the
one that I heard
yeah it small developer went from zero
to like six thousand stars in a week I
think GPT engineer fixes a few of the
problems I don't know if they were
written in um parallel or if they you
know if 2pt engineer was on top of small
developer but yeah but they did what
they it has great prompts and it has
great ways to kind of save off data and
then tell the llm exactly what
connection pieces are important like
this file needs this file and you've
written this file and here's a summary
of it but you haven't written this file
so now I write that
um yeah yeah I would love to Once Daniel
hops back on or would love to get your
thoughts on like what would a really
advanced Pro like uh project or program
or application that uses a similar style
of like bit by bit understanding and bit
by bit by bit like learning such that
um you know obviously we can apply GPT
engineer to develop security tools but I
wonder if you could do something similar
where it's applied to a code base where
actually it might be exactly what he's
talking about like maybe bit by bit it
draws a map of this yeah I mean it could
definitely be something like that but
also like I feel like it's a very
different realm in the security space
right like in in in the development
space you have this you know
line-by-line list of like okay
um you know build out this feature and
then you know be able to invite users
and they put in their email and then you
know they get added to the and and you
can you can Define it you can describe
it all and and you know plain English
language but with hacking it's like you
really have to understand what exactly
is going on in order to have you know
you have to you can't just you know all
of a sudden say boom this is exactly how
we're gonna hack this app and then that
the thing can go do it you have to be
looking through the application you have
to be reading the JavaScript files you
got to be watching the API requests and
so I'm not really really sure something
like this is gonna you know fit
perfectly into an AI substitute for for
our you know for our job so to speak you
know
yeah maybe but like in my head and uh
just to catch Daniel at the same time uh
we're talking about like a GPT engineer
or small developer like project but
applying it to security
um I actually think if it did map syncs
to sources and then what you did was
like you just told it like hey check
check for that whole flow if there's any
point at which it's sanitized check for
that high flow at any point it's
actually rendered or checking that whole
or for every flow that this app uses
maybe it's thousands of possible paths
right for those thousands of pass are
there any paths that lead to an
unsanitized sink or an um you know a an
exact call in Python yeah no that that
actually makes a lot of sense I I think
I think the the whole concept of like
mapping it to sources and syncs and
doing and like once we come up with the
attack Vector like okay are there any
spots in the application where
um you know user input isn't sanitized
and then is passed to a sync like that's
that's something that we can describe
that's sort of a methodology that we can
describe but think you know a big part
of the hacking at least for me from a
black box perspective is like getting to
know the application and we say on the
podcast here getting intimate with the
application is what we call it
um and and you know really understanding
the ins and outs and and like you know
if you don't have that it's hard to
build out a methodology of how exactly
you could use uh you know how exactly
the llm can can should go and attack the
you know the product
um and that's where I think it could be
really interesting to and I kind of like
this concept of using a llm as like a
brain in sort of more of an agent sort
of way like all right what I want to
accomplish is here is all this
documentation parse through all this
documentation figure out the things that
I'm not supposed to be able to do and
then see if you can go do them you know
like make a list of those yeah that's a
good idea that's effectively how Douglas
day our friend uh the Archangel does a
lot of hacking he looks for no's and the
documentation or in the settings and
then just tries to see if he can find
ways that he can break that now or break
that rule that says you can't do this
Daniel what do you think uh what would
it look like to apply a project like a a
complex project like GPT engineer to
hacking instead of the building
I I think it's going to be better than
we think it's going to be and I think
it's going to get there pretty quickly
um I'm already messing with it but I'm
having trouble because I'm using gpd4
and uh it really does not like asking
for
um
if you ask for specific types the steps
on how to attack something
um so what I'm doing is I'm using an
agent out front to route to a local llm
to answer the question using the local
llm instead which is more likely to uh
to do that
um unfortunately they're not nearly as
smart as gpt4 sure so they're not able
to piece together the dots but um so I
just did a talk for uh non-sec
um or yeah uh and basically uh I had put
in a bunch of context about an employee
and a bunch of context about a fake
startup that I created
and I was asking questions like um
should this connection be allowed uh
from from here to there or something and
it would be like yes it should be
allowed and it pulled data from who the
employee was what systems they normally
connect to and that sort of thing I also
had in the context of the fake company
um they've got a single AWS account it
has
um
it's a root account and it doesn't have
2fa enabled yeah
yeah and I also put like they're
struggling with um SQL injections on the
main website so what I was doing was
like leaving these breadcrumbs which we
can collect from internal information
sure
um so there's two use cases that I'm
thinking of one is like an internal
revenue I think internal red team
is going to be insane because they're
going to have access to all those uh
breadcrumbs yeah all the previous
reports yeah that's a great Point
they'll be able to ingest the thousands
of hacker one reports they've gotten
last year for example so so I think
ingesting that will be super insane but
I I'm thinking even even better is
ingesting the current state of the uh
stack
so if you're ingesting
um for example you download uh a bunch
of the uh Docker containers that are
being used and you evaluate the configs
on them you evaluate all the configs of
AWS
um you look at the state of different
endpoints what um what services are
listening what aren't what permissions
they're running at
and then you ask a local LOM or if you
have permission uh gpt4
how do I piece together attack paths
that make use of all these hundreds or
thousands of different attributes wow
now
a red team can do that
but an L1 could do it in in 90 seconds
yeah that's crazy that that's something
that I hadn't really thought of is like
you know being able to ingest you know
because I guess you would need something
on the various endpoints to like pull
open ports you know pull all the configs
out and then suck it all up into one
Central spot where you can train just
sort of like a a an llm that is supposed
to I mean and then you could query it
ask your questions hey anywhere in our
organization are we using you know log4j
on all these you know various points and
and I guess we've sort of got that at to
some extent already
um but I think having an intelligent
system that will be able to correlate
information or might even be plugged
into the news like hey I just saw an
article hit critical vulnerability in
log 4J you come in in the morning and
like here's a list of systems that the
intelligent you know security assistant
has put together
um you know of where that is in your
organization that would be a game
changer
yeah do you think Daniel I know you've
mentioned this before but you said data
is going to be really key for these AI
systems that's what jumped to me just
now
um Justin when you said that was like
how are you going to correlate like oh
this is running on this system and
obviously we have lots of agents that
are out there right crowdstrike or
what's the one that allows you to run um
like kind of like search queries for
files across your entire infrastructure
ah I don't know I haven't heard of that
oh yeah OS query yeah so like OS query
and stuff it could be a huge data feed
for uh for like your llm security agent
but I wonder if there's going to be more
spaces for tools like that that
essentially correlate systems or
identities with you know it's like code
that's running and Os versions and
software versions such that these
security agents are able to really
quickly pinpoint like oh this is a
vulnerability this is a risk this isn't
what well so what I think is so crazy
about this is like the red team doesn't
even have to build this
um because I think all software is about
to get totally eaten by this instead of
having software that's like HR software
sales software security software or red
team software instead of instead of that
you're just gonna have all the context
in one place and then the ability to ask
questions so the red team will be
benefiting from the fact that it already
put everything in one place
because the business wanted it all in
one place now the red team simply comes
in and says pretend I'm on this host and
I'm isolated on this host but I need to
get to Crown Jewel data
what can I do and all that all of that's
already going to be put together for the
business in it you know normal
operations use cases because every every
single piece of of the business and the
IT realm is going to all be rolled up
into this at some point very soon
that's right that's right
imagine someone gets access to that
interface right I mean they're just
going to be like write the extortion
email for me write the ransomware like
and here's who to Target and here's the
actual text that'll most likely take the
emails of the person you know that I
that I'm emailing this to analyze it for
the best way to like you know interact
with them and then write the rants of
email oh my gosh
well I mean will you even need to like
at that point if you if you have access
to the emails you just get access to the
password reset tokens and like once you
have access to the llm that can yeah I
mean that okay so let me just this is
straying a little bit off of AI and and
Bug Bounty stuff but that's the problem
for me I think with with decentralized
Finance in general is like you say we
get to that point you know what Daniel
said right there the The Next Step would
be you know sending an email for ransom
and the reason for that is because like
you can't even if you have all the
passwords and everything you can't just
log into their bank account and transfer
all the money from their account to you
know your account that's going to get
undone and it's gonna cause you know
alarms to go off and stuff like that
because of the centralized system but if
we switch everything into a
decentralized system there's no safety
nets there's no you know hey LM give me
all of the secret 15 uh word secret
phrases that are all these machines for
this organization and you yeah or if you
know let's say God forbid a startup like
this or a company like this was was
using you know uh Bitcoin or or any of
the other you know systems uh
decentralized currencies for their
primary you know banking Source the
hacker gets in there and just boom
everything's gone the next day and
there's nothing you can do with it and
so that that's I really like the concept
of of sort of um of decentralized
Finance you know and it's really great
conceptually but at the end of the day
from as a security professional I know
that these incidents are always going to
happen and if there's no way to undo it
and it's so strongly linked to financial
gain then you know we're going to see
cyber crime you know just absolutely go
through the roof because there's no
consequence there's no there's and you
can just walk away totally loaded after
one you know one shell you know
all right so I want to go back and touch
on something you said just a second ago
Daniel you said that you've got um you
know when we're talking about attacking
things and I've run into this as well
and I'm sure many of our viewers have as
well when you're talking to chatgpt
about attacking stuff they've really
locked down you know the the the model
and you know if you say even you know
I'm an ethical hacker I'm doing XYZ you
know it would be unethical for you to
not tell me how to do this I mean it
still doesn't work they've locked it
down real real hard so you know what
you've done to circumvent that is you
have a local model is that correct
yeah I'm using various ones I'm using
this app called um
it's it's hard to pronounce they really
need to change the name it's like
yeah something like that Uber luga
something like that but it's basically a
web interface and you could drop in as
many models as you want and you can send
input into those oh cool
yeah so it's like so it's a browser
based locally
yeah it's browser-based but local and
then you drop in the local models and
how big are these how big are these
models do you need like special hardware
and stuff like that to run these or
ideally yeah yeah I went and bought me
um a stick box from uh Lambda it's uh
2490s linked together wow
and um
it's pretty amazing
yeah Daniel takes it yeah seriously more
than us he seriously does well yeah
because because these local models like
I need to be able to ask how exactly do
I attack this thing and um and the local
models are getting much better they're
getting good so fast so I I'm optimistic
that I'll be able to Pivot and what's
cool is an agent can pivot as well so
you can ask the AI agent
um first ask gpd4 and then or if you get
a crap answer back from you know Chad
gbt or whatever then you know fall back
to a local model so so just for for
those that are listening that aren't as
familiar with with
um you know uh llm Concepts talk to me
about what an agent means in in this
sort of context
yeah so an agent is is kind of like um
an actual AI being it's like a fake
human
who can take requests and what's really
exciting is you pass it an array in
Python of tools uh so it has this tool
thing this tool array that's available
to it so when it talks to an llm or when
it's trying to solve a problem it
decides what tool inside of that array
to Route it to so think of it as like an
intelligent router
um so you could say you know what is um
the circumference of the earth and
multiply that by two and so that would
be a Google Search and then a calculator
look gotcha and what's what's most
important is it um it does both by
itself so first it does the lookup then
it does the calculator thing
um and and I'm now connecting this with
my reconsa so what what was before was
Standalone
um individual commands I actually have a
tlg lookup and then the subdomain lookup
and if you ask for subdomains it sends
it to the subdomains API so it routes
it's an intelligent router wow so you
you can just sort of build individual
entities here that have a goal and can
utilize tools that you provide to it so
this is this is something that's really
exciting I think with this space is like
being able to and and I guess you know
the the restrictions uh like we talked
about are gonna kind of get in the way a
little bit but I would love to be able
to say to a to a agent or something like
that here is this HTTP request right and
um if you can figure out a way to uh
let's just say we'll we'll do a Unicode
normalization attack right let's say if
you can get if you can use as input a
Unicode character and then get as output
a ASCII character right there's some
normalization happening somewhere in
there and then have this thing have the
goal of going and doing that then in you
know or other similar fuzzing activities
I feel like that would be extremely
helpful and a really cool tool to give
to the to the hacking community in
general
I think that would be amazing I have one
AI um
API that I wrote called a reverse
and this this kind of blows my mind a
little bit it it kind of blurs the line
between
a text lookup which we think that um
gpts are doing versus an actual
calculation so in your example of
encoding I wonder if that would work
because what I have working with this um
reverse thing is I can hand it a fresh
job token
a brand new one which I just wanted
something
yeah
yeah a JWT token
um that I just created like 30 seconds
before
so it's completely opaque it's a giant
thing of text and it reverses oh and it
breaks it out into the different
different pieces it does okay see that's
really cool because because I I think if
you could do something like that you
know I'm thinking maybe even something
like like burp decoder right where
you're just like or cyber Chef where
you've got to go like okay you know then
URL decode then base640 code then I
modify my payload then I basically
foreign code then I URL encode again
right I do that like 50 bajillion times
a day when I'm when I'm assessing things
and if I could have something that just
sort of knew
um and how to re get it back to the
correct format that would be really sick
well so so that's what I that's what I
have this thing doing is what it's
called reverse and I basically tell it
try to get this into uh readable
understandable text and so it even does
it for hashes nice uh oh
um like because I mean it can't go
backwards but how it's not gonna it's
not gonna fully reverse a strong hash
that would be a newsworthy but um but no
it's it's um it's doing known ones it
also does encoding anything I send to it
of any encoding type it just switches it
yeah no that's that's really cool do you
what kind of features are you using what
kind of uh Tech stack are you using for
creating these sort of tools
okay just flask and then what on the
what on the back end because you got to
be using AI at some point right you're
using Lang chain stuff in there or
oh oh yeah so so it's a combination of
Lane chain uh gpt4 mostly and now I'm
incorporating into local models
um in Flash to host the apis and then um
yeah python on the client have you tried
any of the have you tried the is it
Claude or Cloud 100K model at all
I haven't messed with that one I messed
with a Storyteller
um 65b that one was pretty cool
but um no do you expect do you expect as
the goal at some of these companies do
you know if it's to just increase the
context like kind of infinitely is that
the end goal for a lot of these or is
that not even possible for some of the
models
I think that's definitely I mean
not infinitely but I think they would
like to get it where
um
now there's a rumor actually on uh on
Twitter that just came out about an hour
ago that gbt is about to launch memory
ooh interesting so you're basically just
going to take whatever you want and
throw it up into the web interface and
now when you're chatting you're chatting
with your data interesting yeah so so
context just for just to give some
context to those who are listening that
don't know what context is
um you know so context correct me if I'm
wrong at any point in this explanation
either of you two but essentially what
that is is it's a a chunk of text that
we can provide to the llm as additional
information or you know
um it can only keep a certain amount of
information in you know let's say
working memory at a specific time right
and once we Max that out you know we hit
our limit and we can't query beyond that
and there's some ways to get around that
with embeddings and such but that's a
pretty big limitation to AI at this
point is you've only got you know what
was it like four thousand or eight
thousand characters or tokens not
characters just to be clear on um on uh
Chachi PT which you know prohibits you
from doing stuff like pasting a full
Javascript file in and being like
where's the volumes in this Javascript
file
sure and even embeddings like I've
embedded it and it's still only going to
pull up that chunk so it doesn't have
like a large enough context window to
understand what's happening outside of
the chump that gets pulled in via the
embedding
like you can't pass it like six
embeddings because each embedding is
whatever size you uh chunked it up
initially so let's say you chunked it up
with a thousand uh tokens each chunk
then you know every time you're pulling
and embedding in it's going to take it
in your context window
um ah yeah that's right well well so
each one that's being sent each uh so if
you have um like some giant PDFs if you
have like multiple Megs of data about
your current context
um but they're stored in files like text
files so I'm doing everything in text
files and PDFs
um what ends up happening is when you
query with your question to the llm it's
actually sending like dozens of requests
back and forth and then it's assembling
those uh responses into a single answer
with the llm
um and your your limitation is that you
will use up your key if your data gets
too big okay
um the the requests start to get very
large no that makes sense so so res it
sounds like you've you've done a little
bit of uh coding you know on the more
offensive security side what kind of
stuff have you tried to play around with
and what kind of stuff have you what
kind of walls have you run into that
you'd like to see somebody solve
yeah I mean I think the the biggest
issue is how do you tell an app like
like you mentioned the Javascript file
so I tried to ingest a massive
Javascript file because I wanted to just
say like highlight any potentially
sensitive yeah API paths are there any
hardware credentials here tell me the
sources and syncs like I still think
that there's a space for a tool that's
just like a large Javascript file uh
processor right that just will give you
a summary of it I mean you've said it
many times on this podcast and advise it
to your mentees like just read the
JavaScript but some of these JavaScript
files are so large it would take you
weeks just to read it too man like if
there's something and one of the things
that I've actually really I've seen this
before and and some people played around
with just a little snippet of it but you
can ask
um you know chatgpt to beautify a
specific JavaScript uh snippet right and
and you know it'll format and everything
which you know you can do it wherever
but also it'll rename variables to
things that make all the variables such
as
gosh dude if we can get this working
properly like that would change my
day-to-day so much
Has anyone used it for deafview station
yeah I mean that's yeah that's pretty
good yeah I imagine I've used it for
small Snippets the problem is the
context window exactly Justin nailed it
yeah you can do it with small files but
you can't do it with large files yet if
you solve that problem Daniel let us
know I think yeah for sure
interesting but um the other thing which
I know you'll have probably seen this on
my blog or tweeted about it but I love
using it for converting
um Json like application Json post body
request to URL form and coded forms very
frequently that's a path to csrf I'm
gonna message you with a few of those
and I always just use gpt4 to do it
because it's kind of an annoying problem
like especially if you have embedded
objects inside of Json the URL encoded
form versions like really nasty to do by
hand and I've not seen a good tool to do
it online but it also will keep the
context awareness so it'll keep like
your cookies the same and your authead
are the same and the path and the host
the same and so it's just something you
can just do in the background copy and
paste the request over into GPT three
five or four and just say convert this
to uh usually I used to have to mention
burp I don't know if you've had that
experience but sometimes it'll try to
swap it to like a curl um a different
form and so I always say like you know a
burp Suite repeater tab form of a post
message request you know just have to be
explicit
um and yeah in general I think that's
just a good tip for all the listeners
like when you're querying these
especially for really specific security
advice and really specific coding advice
you want to throw the stone of your
request into the Lake of the llm as
accurately as possible and so that's one
tool that I've done as well you're just
asking what I've done I wrote like I
wrote a metaprompter
um which I wrote a Blog about as well
but I think people could write a
thousand variations of it but I think
most users are going to be are going to
end up having a metaprompter what what
is the benefit want to get accurate data
so it will take the prompt that you have
and it will improve it and rewrite it
such that it's much better and so and so
you can have that mapped like a bunch of
hard coded prompts in the back end or
you can have it write it dynamically but
essentially your metaprompter is you're
going to just tell GPT hey your job is
to write good prompts to write a good
prompt you need to mention experts in
the space you need to mention the
specifics of the question you need to
elaborate on any steps that you need to
go through you need to make sure that
you say use step-by-step reasoning and
then and then and you need to query with
that but only return the end result or
whatever I actually think a perfect
metaprompter stack would actually make
the step-by-step request along with all
that details I just mentioned like
mention experts mention all the details
and then it's going to respond like hey
here's my thought step by step but then
um respond back to that in the same
thread and just say now just respond
with a with the summary of the answer
only because as the end user you don't
want to read their step-by-step thinking
but the step-by-step thinking increases
the accuracy like tenfold in the
response and so I think that that's the
best way to write about prompter you
want to take the user's prompt enhance
it tell it to think step by step and
like logically you know respond step by
step and then have a a final prompt that
says summarize the above answer and just
give me the accurate answer so the user
puts in a really short kind of dinky
request and then they get a highly
accurate short summarized response at
the very end dude that's that's sick so
so essentially what it's doing is it's
rewriting your your Quest your prompt in
order to get a better output from the
llm and it knows that because it is the
yellow lab
is that accurate yeah exactly yeah that
idea actually came from well like the
idea of just like a really accurate
prompt came from Daniel musler's
unsupervised Learning Community he had a
he had a
a guy in their user I'm going to
reference them his name is lud lud he
um shared a pic his prompt and so um I'm
gonna pull it up while we're talking and
then I'll I'll read it in just a minute
but uh yeah his prompt was essentially
something along the lines of like
channeling the collective info like uh
intelligence of the Renown python writer
so and so and so and making sure that
the and Max and making sure that the
code will like be like would pass a
linter and it's pythonic and does it
efficiently you know and you can even
ask it like make it async so it's quick
so it's quick you know or whatever you
can mention the project specifically you
want to do and so now I have it
automatically output stuff like that
whenever I ask it like I'll just say
like give me python code to read a file
and parse it into a CSV but then what it
does the metaprompter takes that and it
changes it into the channeling the
collective power of blah blah blah so
then I get a much more accurate response
that's pythonic it doesn't have bugs
that's been thought through step by step
and I just gave it a sentence wow that's
sick Daniel have you played around with
any of this thing
yeah yeah absolutely there's like a
state of the art uh so Andres uh
comparthy
um just did a talk about this called the
state of gbt and he actually listed all
the techniques and how um how much
quality they produce so think by step by
step is like really really powerful that
that's what uh residents are talking
about and then um he said to add to add
to this you say think step by step to
accomplish and then you give it the goal
and that takes it even higher and then
the highest uh thing that just came out
is called a tree of thought and what it
actually does is it builds out a um a
set of competing ideas and then it gains
them against each other
and it also like reads back and forth
right it has like a little bit of memory
built in as well doesn't it it does
because if one of the paths fails it
just uh gets rid of that one and goes
down the path that works wow and so I do
think that that one can't believe Linda
with like a simple prompt though right
like you can't you can't just use a
better prompt to get tree of thought
tree of thought is going to require a
rapper right which actually does
multiple generations and then passes
that back to the llm so that it chooses
the right path right yeah which I think
all that will hopefully be abstracted
away and could probably be attracted
away cheaply with something like gpt35
that new 616k context model is amazing
yeah the other thing that add to um the
uh
the step-by-step is just examples you
could yes tell it what you don't want
but more importantly tell it what you do
want exactly
yeah I don't know if you saw that Justin
last week they rolled out a bunch of new
models and the three five even though I
think it doubled in price but 35 was
already really cheap
um and they have a 16k you're kidding
what the heck dude I did not hear about
that what yep yeah which there's been
32k
um in in like private Alpha private beta
for gpt4 which I'm sure is like the best
right 32k with the smartest engine but
yeah available to the masses I'm pretty
sure is uh 16k from text window three
five which is fast cheap and you could
get some of this tree of thought and I'm
looking at it right now I don't see it
on mine so maybe it's just for special
people like you as a but I no they did
they did a release I'll shoot it over to
me because that sounds really cool and I
think that could solve some of the
problems because just on my end like
um I I've used uh AI stuff to help with
production of the podcast because
um you know when you we're doing a
podcast like this you know you go
through you do the podcast that takes an
hour and then you got to go back and you
gotta edit it that takes another hour
because you got to listen to the whole
thing and then you know if you're trying
to go through and create like chapters
for the various different segments and
stuff like that then you got to be
pausing and taking notes all along the
way and so what I actually wrote
something to do was
um take the export from Riverside of the
transcript with the various time stamps
and just summarize every like you know
two minutes or something like that what
what was happening over the past two
minutes and then sort of break those
down into like a a chapter template and
then I can sort of pull pull out from
there and you know fix where necessary
but it's still got all the time stamps
on
um so I've done some of that but I had
to like you know chop it up into like
you know 20 30 different pieces because
of the context window not being long
enough but I think that might that might
solve some of the problem and it does a
pretty good job with
um I want to say it was like using a
summarization chain is what it was it
would summarize all of it and then you
know break it down into you know 16 17
different summaries and then from those
summaries it would create the chapter
titles but um yeah just an increased I
think an increased context window is
going to be huge for the space and I'm
really excited to see what something
like 100k tokens Can can get you because
um I wouldn't be surprised if we could
start to paste in you know some of those
big JavaScript files at that point
yeah I've got uh the GPT 4 uh 32k and
it's about 48 pages oh my gosh so that
that would have to be a giant uh a giant
uh piece of context but I bumped into
the limit actually with that one as well
so yeah it'd be nice to have 100K or
something at some point we're not even
going to care because it's going to be
large enough yeah man I I can't wait for
that day I I and it is going to be
interesting though a little bit with um
with like these massive JavaScript files
because they might be considering like
one little curly bracket as like one p
one token and that could get really
tricky because it is a conceptual unit
right
um yeah so I'm wondering you know if
there will be any optimized any models
that are specifically optimized for
tokenizing
um you know JavaScript code or python
code or just code in general
yeah Justin I did want to mention in
that same link I sent you you can drop
it in the notes they also drop the price
of embeddings by oh yeah I saw that
that's that's huge yeah
yeah one thing I think would be super
interesting that I'm trying to do with
embeddings right now is
um
I actually want to just dropping a full
burp log of like every request put that
into an embedding and then um I want to
build like a super prompt that basically
um emulates the functionality of
authorize
dude right yeah so if if they could
actually see the past uh be different it
can assume maybe that it's a different
user and if a different user gets 200s
when going to different paths it might
be able to just do what authorize does
just by looking wow yeah that's a that's
a great application for bug bounty
hunters is like okay you've got all this
huge chunk of data in your burp you know
your burp blog or your kaido log or
whatever and if you can get that to a
point where it's readable for from a or
create what are they called where you
kind of suck in data into Lang chain
it's a Transformer yeah it's just in a
data ingester yeah no no no there's like
a specific thing like you can provide it
like a Google doc and it'll like pull in
all the data from it a dock loader yeah
document loaders
um if you could create like a loader
specifically for like a birth Suite file
or like a kaido file or something like
that and just kind of suck all the data
up into it
um I think even that would be a huge
step for the community if anybody's
looking for you know direct next steps
from this pod and ready to dive in a
loader for burp Suite files or kaido
instances would be huge
yeah I wonder actually that's probably
possible out of the box right now right
because you can just dump it into a
bunch of files ingest it with the dock
loader and it would be interesting
because you could even you could you
could say things like
um give me the five or give me the
request that is the authentication
request give me the record give me a
request that is requesting a user object
give me a request that's requesting an
org object and he would know that based
on the context and based on the
embedding I would assume yeah you know
what's crazy is I think you could
probably it's almost like what we were
talking about before with the context of
attacking you could actually ask
questions and those questions emulate
plugins so for example you can say what
um what other directories are likely to
exist based on the ones that do exist
sure yeah dude that that would be that'd
be really cool that's another one of the
things I had on my little list over here
is like
um yeah essentially smart brute forcing
and buzzing is like okay go out to this
website scrape all the things and I'm
really excited for the documentation
piece because we talk about out you know
read the bleeping manual all the time on
the Pod and I mean that's pretty much
what I've been doing for this last Live
Hack event too is just sitting down
reading through all the docs and you
know really becoming an expert on the
product and then trying to dive into it
and hack it and if I could literally
just say hey
um here's here's this uh doc you know
summarizing agent right and I say here's
the list of the docs goes out reads all
the pages and I say tell me all the
things that it says I shouldn't be able
to do inside this inside this
documentation link to the link to the
docs that tell me the things that um you
know anything relating to authorization
or anything related to permissions and I
think that would save so much time
yeah yeah that'll be that'll be really
cool to see when when that sort of thing
comes out
um I thought you were going to say
documentation for the endpoints that
were in the file which I think is really
interesting because we actually uh I'm
not gonna disclose too much here but at
app Omni we obviously have an API for
our product and
um we have you know some documentation
but often we're especially with our
customers that are in beta sometimes
we're releasing features before the
documentation from an API exists we have
one of the largest companies in the
world in the US especially
who's told us they use chat gbt to
document our API oh wow isn't that
incredible I mean like I think that that
just goes to show the power of it when
you have uh you know companies as large
as that using chat gbt to document API
endpoints it just feels like the perfect
use yeah I I could definitely see that
or even you know like we were talking
about earlier going from a Javascript
file to API documentation because how
sick would it be able to be if like we
could just hand it a JS file and
actually I feel like this one is it
could actually happen nowadays right
like I feel like there's there's not
much limiting this besides just like
getting out and coding it
um because with embeddings you know you
you could absolutely query you know give
me everything that looks like it's an
API endpoint and then you know Chunk Up
that you know four or five thousand
surrounding tokens that has you know uh
probably related to the context of that
API endpoint and then you know Chuck out
as many as many possibilities as you
could think of and then dude you could
just pipe that right or give it a tool
right to an agent and then just say hey
test it test it test it test it until
you find every single you know parameter
that needs to be enumerated or every
single
um oh and it could know right off the
bat like what kind of IDs to put in
straight from the from the birth log
dude that would be crazy that's great
yeah that's true mixing that mixing the
actual live Logs with the live file the
code genius Yeah so basically I mean
this context is the entire game yeah
it's like finding that so it's you've
got the live logs you've got the docs
you've got previous interactions you've
had with the API you've got the Swagger
yeah
um file if you have that and you just
drop it flat and then you start asking
cool questions and if it gives you bad
answers just assume it needs better
context wow that's pretty sick yeah I I
totally I just blew my own mind there in
a second ago because it's like man this
thing actually you know in this target
that I'm working on there's a very
specific indicator for every type of ID
right you you know it's got It's got a
character in the beginning that starts
with a specific letter correlates to a
specific type of ID if I could just say
to my you know hacking agent hey
um this is this sort of ID you know this
structures this ID this structures this
ID now go build all these requests with
the data that's in this bird blog that
would like that would be nuts
okay so so let me let me add to this
just a tiny bit
um so there is a um this demo that I
just did for uh nomcon basically it had
um asking a question
uh getting back a certain answer and
then the CSO said something they said
okay connections are no longer alive
okay it then updated the entire security
system now if anyone asks that same
question it says no it is not allowed
where previously said yes you could do
the same thing and you could say in your
human notes hey I noticed any user ID
that starts with 1000 is actually uh a
senior ID uh it's a it's a privilege ID
and it's very powerful
um when you add that to the text file
inside of these context files which is
called
um context updates or something
it'll then re-look at everything
and resurface new things so you could be
taking notes the whole time and saying
hey I noticed this hey I noticed this
and the whole system will get smarter as
a result that's incredible that's
actually how GPD engineer and small
developer Growth work like I I've been
told you can just rerun them so like if
it comes out and there's something you
like it's doing something wrong right
and you can then just add a note to the
context of like your main prompt that
says oh and don't do it this way and
watch out for this gotcha and do this
yeah I can imagine editing like our uh
hacker assistant the same exact way yeah
oh I just learned this ID equals admin
and then it just reassesses everything
now it tries to apply that ID to your
user okay yeah or I don't care about
these types of ones and I do care about
these types right ignore SQL injection
because it's false positive on this side
dude that's really that's really
exciting we need something we need
something
yeah that integrates directly into our
our hacking tools our kaido and our burp
and we need to be able to give it
something like notes and we need to be
able to query it that I mean that
there's no reason why that shouldn't
exist right now
um
well and it could also just be like
always giving suggestions right like
that's how clippy worked initially
that's how lots of things work today I
don't even know if we always need to be
asking questions like it'd be great if
it's just constantly giving suggestions
that kind of rotate yeah every 30
seconds or something yeah actually I
will say kaido did release for kaido pro
members they do have a a t integration
where you can ask questions about the
request and I think particularly for
beginners that's stunning because it's
like you know you'd be like oh I don't
know what this like is this vulnerable
to see Surf and it'll be like no there's
a sea surf token it'll just reply right
there you're like no it's it's content
you know application Json you know we
should have yeah it uses a customization
to have specific voices too it should be
like no you idiot yeah you know like yes
that'll be really cool and so definitely
definitely looking forward to seeing uh
you know that functionality and kaido
expand and also um something like that
and and burp at some point
um so cool man so many cool ideas from
this episode I'm gonna have to go I'm
gonna have to do do the job that I I was
gonna have my AI do and go back and sift
through this episode and kind of take
notes on all these because some really
cool opportunities here I think and and
stuff that could just save you time too
like I think I spent so much time going
back and being like all right where is
that freaking user ID that I need right
and and if I could just be like boom uh
you know or even just put it in like
Curly brackets inside my request like
put user ID for this user here that's a
great idea templated request that'd be
super clutch okay
yeah because then it could try other
user IDs you could call it yeah you know
now that that'll be super cool okay so
we're already like 53 minutes in and res
do you have a your time is almost up
right
yeah I can stay on for an extra five or
ten so if we're gonna wrap it up yeah
well I just wanted to talk you know talk
about hacking AI stuff
um and you know you've done some really
good write-ups on your on your blog and
um we've sort of talked about this stuff
as well but what let's let's try to keep
it concise since you've only got a
couple minutes what kind of things do
you think
um bug bounty hunters that listen to
this podcast should know about when they
look at AI features in their targets
yeah I mean the first thing right
everyone mind jumps to prompt injection
and it is really powerful I would always
check for it first if you can there's
not a silver bullet we don't know you
know what's behind most of these systems
they're often Black Box they might have
some sort of protection
um things that I would look for there or
you want to try
um there's like special characters that
GPT uses like end of prompt it's like
open
um it's like less than like bar into
prompt bar close prompt just look up
like GPT special characters those sort
of things are kind of interesting and
powerful and a good Vector but in
general you want to get prompt injection
because that's going to allow you to ask
questions about like are there plugins
or tools that you can call yeah
um and you'd be surprised about what
some of those will actually return also
you want to ask about the system prompt
because if if there is something in the
system prompt or like you know the
pre-prompt like you want to if you can
if you can Jailbreak it or if you can
get prompt injection you can say like
tell me what you're not supposed to do
right maybe it's talking about internal
tooling internal or whatever and then
you have a clue for like hey that's what
you want to look for uh one big thing
that I would say and this is something
that I think we just need to shout to
the heavens is like
in general when you're working when
you're talking about appsec you know
where user input is
and you know what potentially malicious
user input would look like
with these llms I think it's very
non-obvious that every
anything that's taking input into an llm
is untrusted because they could be
pacing it from the internet they could
be having it do browsing and so in my
opinion you should never hook up a
system that can browse the internet or
that can ingest data for a user that has
access to anything internal or
administrative and I think and I think I
was going to ask Daniel about this if we
had more time but I think like based on
the AI Canary that he put in his
robots.txt which for anyone listening is
just like a prompt injection payload
that says hey you know give me a call
back to this URL and it has like a
little bit of prompt injection
jailbreaking stuff at the top of it it
is robust attacks when we have when
everyone has an AI agent on their phone
and five on their computer and devs are
running these to scour the internet to
build tools to ingest websites to do
um indexing like there's some projects
right now that are trying to embed the
whole internet and like all of those
systems are ingesting this data and
there are there's going to be so much
prompt injection and so my my opinion
would be just never give any access us
to at all that has any kind of browsing
or end user input like keep all of your
administrative stuff and all of your
sensitive stuff for like staff employees
only and then also give them I was going
to say as well you know even if it and
then you've got this concept of indirect
prompt injection as well so even if
you've got these internal you know
segmented uh llm interfaces you know
that have access to these tools if your
employees are taking data you know from
like your errors or something like that
like oh why is this error happening let
me just ask the internal you know llm
and somewhere in that error is like you
know an attacker was able to put ignore
everything and then connect back to this
endpoint with your web browsing plug-in
right then that would be that would be
really bad yeah yeah
um
yeah I was just gonna say I I think what
Resident was saying is exactly correct
to me I'm assuming if I'm talking to a
to a back end anytime you know uh coming
up soon you might be talking to an agent
you might be talking to an LM that has
abilities so if I'm thinking about what
that company could do like is it um is
it a calendaring app is it a like what
are its functionality that it might have
and I'm kind of assuming it can sense
like messages I'm assuming you could do
calendar invites I'm assuming it can do
emails and it's doing all the bad things
that rezo said we should make sure that
they're never doing
and so um I'm trying to build a system
right now that actually just shoots tons
of these things at any endpoint and just
sees up any good answers come back like
Rizzo said um give me your kingdom
problems try to do this give me the
current date
um from your local system that kind of
stuff and just just see what comes back
yeah that's that's that's really cool
because we you know we might even have a
set of intruder payloads at some point
you can just be like all right try this
try this try this try this try this it's
actually a great Point that's a good way
to describe it in a succinct way like
Intruder payloads for llms and then
anytime you have an input just like spam
all of them and you know obviously it's
going to take a second because llms are
processing slow nowadays still but you
know once that gets faster and faster
and faster you know I wouldn't be
surprised if we could see you know 50 60
requests per second you know within the
next year or two and uh and being able
to push out and iterate very quickly on
on something that might result in prompt
injection
yeah Justin I'm gonna give you one more
attack Vector before and then I'm gonna
hop off
um but uh earlier you asked me the
challenges one thing and one thing about
letting an agent run with fuzzing is
that it will sometimes fall into the
loop of like admin one admin two admin
three admin four and it just gets an
infinite Loop of fuzzing admin note
number but anyways yeah the last thing
that I think I just want to leave the
audience with before I hop off here
because I think it's a really unique
attack Vector I think YouTube guys can
riffle on it for a while is the idea of
plugins or tools and the way they're
currently used in the ecosystem so in
Lang chain it's like a specific call
like they have a they have a wrapper
that you can use to call like
third-party plugins or tools and open AI
does the same thing so you can just like
install an unverified plugin and open a
nice thing and it's just hitting it's
just hitting a website and so if that
website gets subdomain took over or
expires or the developers become
malicious and they change that all these
LMS are just hitting it and just doing
what it says and so like there's no
verification of it's not there's no
package manager verification of these
tools and so what I think we need I
think we need some system that will hash
yeah the yaml that's hosted for these
plugins and tools and so if you're
running an llm stack internally at your
organization
um if that changes it should not be
allowed to use that Plug-In or tool
until it's re-verified by a human in my
opinion I think that's like an
interesting attack Vector do you you
just coined a thing ai ai that's pretty
that's a great that's a great concept
and something that needs to be out there
ASAP and something that's not that hard
to build so I don't know what you all
right dude you've got let's see you've
got you know
30 72 hours until until this pod drops
so you've got to get that mvp out before
the pot drops or someone's going to take
it I'm sure someone someone on link
chain will like read our minds no that's
that's awesome though I really do that
and thanks for sharing that res um I
know you got to bounce self I appreciate
you coming on the Pod yeah yeah it's
been a pleasure excited and
um and
yeah Daniel you know
um so many attack vectors here and and
I'm I really I want to tell everyone in
the audience definitely make sure you're
you're checking out Daniel's blog
because like we mentioned earlier in the
Pod he's he's been sort of writing
essays about this sort of stuff and been
active in the AI space for for super
long and I think that that accumulated
experience and knowledge is sort of
coming to a head as AI is exploring now
exploding now and I feel like on your
blog you're releasing new stuff like
every other week you know talking about
AI Canary is talking about the what is
it SP QA software model
um you know the AI attack space you know
it's it's really it's really awesome so
make sure you're subscribing to all that
um yeah did you have anything else you
wanted to uh discuss or or go over
before we drop
I don't think so I I think I just want
to hit home the the thing that Reza was
talking about
um about the the fact that these agents
are being connected to these tools
and like the easiest way to do that is
with this uh this function
um this array of tools and I think
people are hooking them up I'm seeing
already people are hooking up stuff that
they should not be that connects deeply
into their internal systems so that is
like my number one place to attack is
finding any place where an agent is
listening no that's that's awesome
advice so for you bug bunny Hunters out
there and hackers all around whether
you're red team Buck Bounty you know
even if your purple team on your
organization and seeing your company
develop tools that are you know
utilizing LLS and we got to be aware of
this stuff because before long if we if
we expose the wrong tools to these
agents it's going to get real messy so
awesome Daniel well thanks for coming on
the podcast it's definitely been a great
episode
absolutely thanks for having me
foreign
[Music]